Guide to the Media Services records, [ca. 1950-2015.]
Media Services records, [ca. 1950-2015]
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Media Services records, [ca. 1950-2015.]
21-36-2566
Cornell University.Media Services.
111.1 cubic ft. 3800+ video tapes. 71+ DVDs. 77+ CDs. 26+ audio tapes.
Films, sound recordings, slide sets, videotapes, CDs, DVDs and inventories.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Film prints (sole surviving copies of very old films) and film printing materials (for which there is no film print or video copy) including films on topics in agriculture, home economics, and general Cornell topics. Also, audio recordings, slide sets and inventories and other items produced by Media Services and Technology Group.
ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
In 2003, the Educational Television Center from Media and Technology Services joined CIT. The Educational Television Center provides video production services ranging from basic professional recordings to public television documentary and entertainment programs. It also houses Cornell's satellite television services. Its studio facility has been the point of origin for numerous live national satellite video conferences and the venue for Cornell faculty and area experts appearing on network television. The Cornell Information Technologies Integrated Audio and Video Engineering group, which formed from Classroom Technologies and Video Collaborative Services, inherited some of the tape archive as well as the functions of the Media Services Group, though they technically do not organizationally descend from Media Services.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Audio visual materials produced by Media Services and the Technology Services Group. Film prints (sole surviving copies of very old films) and film printing materials (for which there is no film print or video copy) including movie films on topics in agriculture, home economics, and general Cornell topics. Also, audio recordings, slide sets, videotapes,and inventories. videotapes, audiotapes, CDs, DVDs, etc. produced by the Media Services and Technology Group. Projects include videos about the Cornell Chimes/McGraw Tower restoration, Cornell's 9/11 "Day of Remembrance, September 14, 2001. Cornell Honors the Victims of the September 11th Terrorist Attacks on America" (V-1451) and the university's annual Commencement, all distributed worldwide. Collection also contains digital files created by the Cornell Information Technologies Integrated Audio and Video Engineering group.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Cornell University.; Rhodes, Frank Harold Trevor.; Cornell University--Administration.; Cornell University--Description--Views.; New York State College of Agriculture and Life Sciences.; New York State College of Home Economics.; New York State College of Human Ecology.; Cornell Information Technologies. Distributed Learning Services.; Cornell University. ‡b Media Services. Distribution Center.
Form and Genre Terms:
Videocassettes.; Videotapes .; Slides (Photography).; Motion pictures (visual works).; Sound recordings.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Several of the films in this collection have been digitized and are available on Cornell's Media Space website. See also links for individual films within the body of this finding aid.
RELATED MATERIALS
See also Media Services Publications, #21-36-2729
SERIES LIST
Series I. Films
Contains some DVD copies of films
Boxes 1-7, 9, 12, 18-24, 26-27, 29-30
Series II. Audiotapes
Boxes 8, 10-14
Series III. Slides
Boxes 16-17, 25
Series IV. Videotapes
Contains some DVD copies of videotapes
Boxes 16-17, 25, 31-33
Subseries IVa. Videotapes transferred from Distributed Learning Services
These items form Boxes 1-78 of sub collection #35-14-3773
Series V. Audiovisual Catalogs
Box 36
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I: Films
  - "Garden-Wise" Monsanto Chemical Corp. - Non-Cornell Film - This film can be viewed in the Prelinger Archive, http://archive.org/details/prelinger., Circa 1950s; F-1051 (Box 21-36-2566 - 1?)
  - "Playschool Observations" I, II, III, IV; Orig. B/W; 3 sets - Cornell Film, September 1966 (Box 21-36-2566 - 1)
  - "A Closer look- Comparative Shopping" Pix A, Pix B, W/P, A-wind Neg. Sound - Cornell Film (Box 21-36-2566 - 1)
  - "Bugs # 3-Flour Beetle"; Pix B, W/P - Cornell Film (Box 21-36-2566 - 1)
  - "Introducing Sugar Beets to New York State" Pix A, Pix B, Photo W/P - Cornell Film (Box 21-36-2566 - 1)
  - "Feeding Roughage to Dairy Cattle" Pix A, Pix B, Photo W/P - Cornell Film (Box 21-36-2566 - 1)
  - "Maple Syrup", "Poison Ivy" Pix B - Cornell Film (Box 21-36-2566 - 1)
  - "A Closer Look" - A feature on European Chafer, 4 min. 30 seconds - Cornell Film (Box 21-36-2566 - 1)
  - 2 Titles "C' Lake Trout" and "Agri Town USA, a Closer Look" - Cornell Film (Box 21-36-2566 - 2)
  - "A Time for Learning" Pix A, Pix B, Photo W/P; B/W - Cornell Film (Box 21-36-2566 - 2)
  - "Food For People" Pix A, Pix B 2 copies - Cornell Film (Box 21-36-2566 - 2)
  - "4H Automotive Program" Single Pix - Cornell Film (Box 21-36-2566 - 2)
  - "Nutrition Sense + Nonsense (revised)" Pix A, Pix B, Photo W/P - Cornell Film (Box 21-36-2566 - 2)
  - "Rolls 4,5+6" - Cornell Film (Box 21-36-2566 - 2)
  - "Report From Cornell" Pix A, Pix B, Photo W/P; B/W Original Rev. - Cornell Film (Box 21-36-2566 - 2)
  - "Take Earle Orig Outs Talk" - Cornell Film (Box 21-36-2566 - 2)
  - "4H Leader Spots" W/P - Cornell Film (Box 21-36-2566 - 2)
  - "Mechanical grape Harvester" Pix A 3 copies, Pix B 2 copies Mask A 2 copies, Mask B 2 copies, Photo W/P - Cornell Film (Box 21-36-2566 - 2)
  - "Bean Harvester" Pix A, Pix B, Photo W/P, Mask A, Mask B - Cornell Film (Box 21-36-2566 - 2)
  - "No More Secrets" Written by Oralee Wachter, Illustrations by Jane Aaron; Film for children on the subject of sexual abuse - Non-Cornell Film, 13mins (Box 21-36-2566 - 3)
  - "Potassium For Agriculture" - Non-Cornell Film, Approx. 25mins (Box 21-36-2566 - 3)
  - "Pleasure is Mutual: How to conduct Effective Picture Book Programs " - Non-Cornell Film, 1967; Approx. 25mins (Box 21-36-2566 - 3)
  - "The Place To Be" - Non-Cornell Film, Approx. 15mins (Box 21-36-2566 - 3)
  - "One With This World" - Non-Cornell Film (Box 21-36-2566 - 3)
  - "Nobody's Perfect" - Non-Cornell Film, Approx. 24mins (Box 21-36-2566 - 3)
  - "No Better Gift" Copy 1; Film about the nutrition of children 1 to 5 years old - Non-Cornell Film, 1984; 22mins (Box 21-36-2566 - 3)
  - "Little Blocks" Copy 1 - Non-Cornell Film (Box 21-36-2566 - 3)
  - "Nutrition- Stan's Secret" - Non-Cornell Film, Approx. 30mins (Box 21-36-2566 - 3)
  - "A Nose for News" - Non-Cornell Film, Approx 25mins (Box 21-36-2566 - 3)
  - "Parents are Teachers Too" - Cornell Film (Box 21-36-2566 - 4)
  - "Joyful Noises" Prepared by Jennifer Birckmayer; Various situations contributing to the language development of young children; - Cornell Film, 15mins (Box 21-36-2566 - 4)
  - "Safe Handling of Foods in Quantity" Copy 1 - Cornell Film, Feb. 1970; 15mins (Box 21-36-2566 - 4)
  - "Safe Operation of the Backhoe and Bulldozer" Copy 2 - Cornell Film, Approx 12mins (Box 21-36-2566 - 4)
  - "Potato Late Blight- Epidemiology" Copy 1 - Cornell Film, Approx 15mins (Box 21-36-2566 - 4)
  - "Pressure Canning Update" Copy 1 - Cornell Film, Approx 17mins (Box 21-36-2566 - 4)
  - "Pest Control and the Environment" Copy 1; 16mm, and VHS - Cornell Film, 13mins (Box 21-36-2566 - 4)
  - "My Art Is Me" By Thelma Harms; Film about the affect of art on young children - Non-Cornell Film, Approx 22mins (Box 21-36-2566 - 5)
  - "My Mother-My Father: Caring For The Aging; by James Vanden Bosch, and Patricia Connelley - Non-Cornell Film, Approx 33mins (Box 21-36-2566 - 5)
  - "Matter of Time" - Non-Cornell Film, Approx. 25mins (Box 21-36-2566 - 5)
  - "Lost in the Woods" - Non-Cornell Film (Box 21-36-2566 - 5)
  - "John Baker's Last Race" -Non-Cornell Film, Approx. 35mins (Box 21-36-2566 - 5)
  - "Jenny is a Good Thing" Copy 1 -Non-Cornell Film, 1969; Approx. 20mins (Box 21-36-2566 - 5)
  - "Interviewing the Abused Child" Copy 1 -Non-Cornell Film, Approx 22mins (Box 21-36-2566 - 5)
  - "Incest the Victim Nobody Believes" Copy 1 - Non-Cornell Film, Approx 20mins (Box 21-36-2566 - 5)
  - "Hello, I Need to Tell You Something." - Non-Cornell Film (Box 21-36-2566 - 5)
  - "New Beginnings" - Cornell Film, 1986; F-841 (Box 21-36-2566 - 22)
  - "Food Science At Cornell" -Cornell Film, F-852 (Box 21-36-2566 - 22)
  - "Food Science At Cornell" - 8mm, F-853 (Box 21-36-2566 - 22)
  - "Backyard Maple Syrup" Sirup [sp] Copy 1; Film shows some residents of the rural northeast tapping their sugar maple trees to make their own maple syrup. -Cornell Film, F-854; 11mins (Box 21-36-2566 - 22)
  - "The American Bald Eagle" Copy 2-Cornell Film, F-855; 16mins (Box 21-36-2566 - 22)
  - "Family Matters" Copy 3; By David Gluck, and Peter Carroll; Documentary that illustrates the effects of societal forces on the family - Cornell Film, 1985; F-856; 29mins (Box 21-36-2566 - 22)
  - "Family Matters" - Film discussion guide, 1985 (Box 21-36-2566 - 22)
  - "Furniture Refinishing" - Cornell Film, F-857; Approx 20mins (Box 21-36-2566 - 22)
  - "Fuel From the Forest" Copy 1 - Cornell Film, F-858; Approx 30mins (Box 21-36-2566 - 22)
  - "Four Nursery Schools" Copy 1 - Cornell Film. (Use DVD-1003 in same box), F-859; Approx 30mins (Box 21-36-2566 - 22)
    Click here to see a digitized version of the film.
    This film examines four nursery school environments. The first is the nursery school at Cornell University that is part of the College of Home Economics, the second is the nursery school for children with special needs at St. Christopher's Hospital for Children, part of Temple University's School of Medicine, the third is the School of Home Economics Children's Center at Syracuse University and forth is the Philadelphia Experimental Nursery School Program. Project participants include Clara P. Baldwin, Helen T. M. Bayer, and Laurel Hodgkin.
  - "Four Nursery Schools" Copy 1 - Copy of F-859, DVD-1003; Approx 30mins (Box 21-36-2566 - 22)
  - "Four Nursery Schools" - Film discussion guide, 1965 (Box 21-36-2566 - 22)
  - "Four Nursery Schools" - Cornell Film, 1965; F-838 (Box 21-36-2566 - 22)
  - "Flower Arrangement on a Budget" Copy 1 - Cornell Film (Use DVD-123 in Box 15), 1963; F-860 (Box 21-36-2566 - 22)
  - "Flower Arrangement on a Budget" - Copy of F-860, 1963; DVD-123 (Box 21-36-2566 - 15)
  - "Daylight Savings: Four Seasons Solar Homes" Copy 1 - Cornell Film (also on video), F-861; Approx 25mins (Box 21-36-2566 - 22)
  - "Learning and Growing and Learning" - Non-Cornell Film, Approx. 20mins (Box 21-36-2566 - 23)
  - "Head Start, It Really Works" - Non-Cornell Film, Approx. 15mins (Box 21-36-2566 - 23)
  - "Hazardous Waste: The Search for Solutions" - Non-Cornell Film, Approx 33mins (Box 21-36-2566 - 23)
  - "Habitat: A Special Place" - Non-Cornell Film, Approx 30mins (Box 21-36-2566 - 23)
  - "Great Expectations" Copy 1; A film for pregnant women and nursing mothers; By Jean Mayer - Non-Cornell Film, 1975; 22mins (Box 21-36-2566 - 23)
  - "Four Families, Part 1" - Non-Cornell Film (Box 21-36-2566 - 23)
  - "Four Families, Part 2" - Non-Cornell Film, Approx. 30mins (Box 21-36-2566 - 23)
  - "Flower Arrangements of Williamsburg" Copy 1 - Non-Cornell Film (Box 21-36-2566 - 23)
  - "The First Signs Of April: The Need For Early Stimulation" - Non-Cornell Film, Approx. 22mins (Box 21-36-2566 - 23)
  - "Safe Use of The Crop-Harvesting Machinery" Copy 2 -Cornell Film, F-862; Approx 15mins (Box 21-36-2566 - 24)
  - "Two Ball Games" - Cornell Film (2 copes). (Use DVD-1000 in same box), 1975; F-863; Approx 30mins (Box 21-36-2566 - 24)
    Captures the difference between two baseball games being played by children. One is a informal game in a park in Fall Creek, Ithaca and the other is a formal Little League game in Auburn, New York. Produced by the College of Human Ecology and the Department of Psychology.
  - "Two Ball Games" - Copy of F-863, DVD-1000; Approx 30mins (Box 21-36-2566 - 24)
  - "Until I Get Caught" A Film on Drinking and Driving - Cornell Film, F-864; 27mins (Box 21-36-2566 - 24)
  - "Until I Get Caught" A Film on Drinking and Driving - Teachers' guide (Box 21-36-2566 - 24)
  - "Sidewalk of Shade" Copy 2 - Cornell Film (also on video), F-865; Approx 30mins (Box 21-36-2566 - 24)
  - "Land Drainage" Copy 1 - Cornell Film (also on video), F-866 (Box 21-36-2566 - 24)
  - "Cornell" - Cornell Film, f-867; Approx 30mins (Box 21-36-2566 - 24)
  - "A Conversation With Helen" Copy 1 - Cornell Film, 1977; F-868; Approx. 35mins (Box 21-36-2566 - 24)
  - Home Economics in the Modern University - Cornell Film, F-869 (Box 21-36-2566 - 24)
    Promotional film made in the mid-1960s for the College of Home Economics, now Human Ecology. Reviews life at Cornell University and courses of study within the College of Home Economics such as nutrition, design and child development. The film also discusses how a degree in Home Economics can lead to a professional career.
  - Home Economics in the Modern University - Copy of F-869, DVD-996 (Box 21-36-2566 - 24)
  - "Country Roads: Safe Driving in the Country" - Non-Cornell Film, 14mins (Box 21-36-2566 - 9)
  - "The County Fair" - Non-Cornell Film, Approx. 30mins (Box 21-36-2566 - 9)
  - "Cry Sorrow, Cry Hope" Reel 1 - Non-Cornell Film, Approx. 24mins (Box 21-36-2566 - 9)
  - "Cry Sorrow, Cry Hope" Reel 2 - Non-Cornell Film, Approx. 33mins (Box 21-36-2566 - 9)
  - "A Cry of Pain" Copy 1 - Non-Cornell Film, Approx. 16mins (Box 21-36-2566 - 9)
  - "Co-Therapy With Parent Group" - Non-Cornell Film (Box 21-36-2566 - 9)
  - "Design for Living" - Non-Cornell Film, Approx 20mins (Box 21-36-2566 - 9)
  - "A Child is Born" Copy 2 Traces a couple's life from when they decide to have a baby until the baby is born - Non-Cornell Film, 22mins (Box 21-36-2566 - 9)
  - "Child Abuse Cradle of Violence" Copy 1- Non-Cornell Film (Box 21-36-2566 - 9)
  - "Are you Listening?" A film designed to teach people how to listen - Non-Cornell Film (Box 21-36-2566 - 26)
  - "Around the Way With Kareema" Copy 1 - Non-Cornell Film (Box 21-36-2566 - 26)
  - "Barb: Breaking the Cycle: of Child Abuse" Copy 1 - Non-Cornell Film, Approx. 30mins (Box 21-36-2566 - 26)
  - "Battered Women: Violence Behind Closed Doors" - Non-Cornell Film (Box 21-36-2566 - 26)
  - "Battered Spouses" - Non-Cornell Film, Approx 27mins (Box 21-36-2566 - 26)
  - "Battered Wives" - Non-Cornell Film, Approx. 30mins (Box 21-36-2566 - 26)
  - "Blocks?A Medium for Perceptual Learning" - Non-Cornell Film, Approx 20mins (Box 21-36-2566 - 26)
  - "Borderline Case: Conference: Part 1 and Part 2" - Non-Cornell Film (Box 21-36-2566 - 26)
  - "Build a Better Bag Lunch" - Non-Cornell Film (Box 21-36-2566 - 26)
  - "When Should Grown-ups Help" Copy 1 - Non-Cornell Film (Box 21-36-2566 - 27)
  - "Water Play" - Non-Cornell Film (Box 21-36-2566 - 27)
  - "View From the Crib" - Non-Cornell Film (Box 21-36-2566 - 27)
  - "Saved From the Pond" - Non-Cornell Film (Box 21-36-2566 - 27)
  - "Special Children, Special Needs" Copy 1 - Non-Cornell Film (Box 21-36-2566 - 27)
  - "Second Chance: Child Abuse" Copy 1 - Non-Cornell Film, Approx 15mins (Box 21-36-2566 - 27)
  - "Spice of Life" Copy 1 - Non-Cornell Film, Approx 10mins (Box 21-36-2566 - 27)
  - "Raising Michael Alone" Copy 1 - Non-Cornell Film (Box 21-36-2566 - 27)
  - "Room To Grow" This Film tries to introduce inner-city children to plant life - Non-Cornell Film (Box 21-36-2566 - 27)
  - "Who Do I Tell?" Copy 1; A film to help sort out problems - Non-Cornell Film (Box 21-36-2566 - 27)
  - "Story Time" Copy 1 - Non-Cornell Film, Approx. 6mins (Box 21-36-2566 - 27)
  - "Racing Cars" Copy 1 - Non-Cornell Film (Box 21-36-2566 - 27)
  - "The Last Thing on My Mind" -- Cornell film (also on video), March 6, 1973 (Box 21-36-2566 - 27)
  - "From My Point of View" Copy 1 - Non-Cornell Film (Box 21-36-2566 - 6)
  - "Clay Play" Copy 1 - Non-Cornell Film (Box 21-36-2566 - 6)
  - "Clay Play" Copy 2 - Non-Cornell Film (Box 21-36-2566 - 6)
  - "For The Rest of Your Life" - Non-Cornell Film, Approx. 15mins (Box 21-36-2566 - 6)
  - "First Food" Copy 1 - Non-Cornell Film, Approx. 17mins (Box 21-36-2566 - 6)
  - "First Friends" Film shows how preschoolers transition into becoming group members - Non-Cornell Film, 22mins (Box 21-36-2566 - 6)
  - "Don't Get Stuck There" - Non-Cornell Film, Approx. 15mins (Box 21-36-2566 - 6)
  - "Discipline and Self-Control" By Jeannette W. Galambos - Non-Cornell Film, Approx. 25mins (Box 21-36-2566 - 6)
  - "Decision at Delano" - Non-Cornell Film, Approx 30mins (Box 21-36-2566 - 6)
  - "Fire Extinguishers: The First Responders" - Non-Cornell Film (Box 21-36-2566 - 6)
  - "Roots of Empire" Copy 1; Directed by Elmer Philips; The story of the vitality of New York State's agriculture - Cornell Film, 28mins (Box 21-36-2566 - 29)
  - "Teacher, Lester Bit me" - Unidentified Film (Box 21-36-2566 - 29)
  - "Secrets of the Plant World" Approx.15mins - Unidentified Film (Box 21-36-2566 - 29)
  - "28-Grams of Prevention" - Unidentified Film (Box 21-36-2566 - 29)
  - "Home Heating With Wood" - Cornell Film (also on video), November 21, 1978; Approx 22mins (Box 21-36-2566 - 29)
  - "Update on Agriculture at Cornell" - Cornell Film, 1975; Approx. 25mins (Box 21-36-2566 - 29)
  - "Sara has Down's Syndrome" Copy 1 - Unidentified Film, Approx. 17mins (Box 21-36-2566 - 29)
  - "Tractor Safety is no Accident" Copy 2 - Unidentified Film, Approx. 17mins (Box 21-36-2566 - 29)
  - "The Time of Your Life" Based on Alan Lakein's book "How to Get Control of Your Time and Your Life"; Remake of original; Film's key idea is "To waste time is to waste your life" - Non-Cornell Film (also on video), 28mins (Box 21-36-2566 - 30)
  - "World of the Beaver" - Unidentified Film, 1971; Approx. 35 mins. (Box 21-36-2566 - 29)
  - "Wagon Safety" Copy 2 - Unidentified Film (Box 21-36-2566 - 29)
  - "A Young Child is" - Unidentified Film, Approx. 24mins (Box 21-36-2566 - 15)
  - "Work and Family: Walking a Tightrope" - Unidentified Film, Approx. 33mins (Box 21-36-2566 - 15)
  - "This is the Mallard" - Unidentified Film (Box 21-36-2566 - 15)
  - "The River" B/W; Film and VHS - Unidentified Film, 31mins (Box 21-36-2566 - 15)
  - "Poisonous Plants" Film and VHS - Unidentified Film, Approx 30mins (Box 21-36-2566 - 15)
  - "To A Babysitter" - Unidentified Film, Approx 20mins (Box 21-36-2566 - 15)
  - "You're Not Communicating" - Unidentified Film (Box 21-36-2566 - 15)
  - "Potato Late Blight - Epidemiology" Copy 2 - Unidentified Film, Approx 15mins (Box 21-36-2566 - 30)
  - "Child Abuse: A Total Treatment Perspective" - 2 copies - Cornell Film (also on video) (Box 21-36-2566 - 30)
  - "Child Abuse: A Perspective on Being a Parent"- 2 copies - Cornell Film (also on video), 1977 (Box 21-36-2566 - 30)
  - "Backyard Maple Syrup" Copy 2 - Unidentified Film, 11mins (Box 21-36-2566 - 30)
  - "On Their Own With Our Help" Copy 1 - Unidentified Film (Box 21-36-2566 - 7)
  - "Farm Tractor Safety" Copy 2 - Unidentified Film (Box 21-36-2566 - 7)
  - "Donald's Fire Survival Plan" - Non-Cornell Film (Box 21-36-2566 - 7)
  - "Bonsai" - Unidentified Film - Unidentified Film, Approx 20mins (Box 21-36-2566 - 7)
  - "Eye of the Storm" A Film on Prejudice and the Martin Luther King Shooting" - Non-Cornell Film, 25mins (Box 21-36-2566 - 7)
  - "Eye of the Beholder" A Film that Shows Appearances Can Be Misleading - Non-Cornell Film, 25mins (Box 21-36-2566 - 7)
  - "A Team of Two" - Unidentified Film, Approx 30mins (Box 21-36-2566 - 7)
  - "Cartoons" B/W; Mighty Mouse, Danger Trail, Andy's Garden, Howdy Dowdie - Non-Cornell Film (Box 21-36-2566 - 7)
  - "Child's Play and the Real World" - Unidentified Film (Box 21-36-2566 - 7)
  - "Agricultural Tractor Safety" Copy 1 - Unidentified Film, Approx 20mins (Box 21-36-2566 - 7)
  - "Arranging Flowers in Your Home" - Cornell Film, 1959 (Box 21-36-2566 - 18)
  - "Budget Flower Arrangement" - Cornell Film (Use DVD-123 in Box 15), 1963 (Box 21-36-2566 - 18)
  - "Biological Control of Snails - Cornell Film (Use DVD-148 in Box 15), 1974 (Box 21-36-2566 - 18)
  - "Biological Control of Snails", 1974; DVD-148 (Box 21-36-2566 - 15)
  - "Bulk Milk - From Farm to Plant" - Cornell Film, 1977 (Box 21-36-2566 - 18)
  - "Common Ground" - Cornell Film, 1975 (Box 21-36-2566 - 18)
  - "Conversation with Helen, A" - Cornell Film-Educational Television Center, 1975 (Box 21-36-2566 - 18)
  - "Daylight Savings: Four-Season Solar Homes" - Cornell Film (also on video), 1982 (Box 21-36-2566 - 18)
  - "Drugs that Affect the Mind" - Cornell Film (also on video), 1971 (Box 21-36-2566 - 18)
  - "Forgotten New Yorkers, The" - Cornell Film, 1973 (Box 21-36-2566 - 18)
  - "Freezing with Confidence - The Science and Art of Home Freezing" - Cornell Film, 1964 (Box 21-36-2566 - 18)
  - "Cheddar Cheese - New York Style" - Cornell Film, 1973; F-836 (Box 21-36-2566 - 18-19)
  - "Cheddar Cheese - New York Style" - 8mm reel, 1973; F-837 (Box 21-36-2566 - 19)
  - "Fibers to Fashion" - Cornell Film, 1973; F-825 (Box 21-36-2566 - 19)
  - "Gabriel is Two Days Old" - published by Educational Development Center, 1974; F-826 (Box 21-36-2566 - 19)
  - "Growing Embryo, The" - Cornell Film-Dept. of Communication Arts, 1969; F-827 (Box 21-36-2566 - 19)
  - "Housing Options for Older People" - Cornell Film (also on video), 1974; F-828 (Box 21-36-2566 - 19)
  - "It Works for Us" -Cornell Film-Audio Visual Resource Center, 1980; F-829 (Box 21-36-2566 - 19)
  - "It Works for Us" - study guide to accompany the film, 1980 (Box 21-36-2566 - 19)
  - "It's Your Money #3: Variations and Options" - Cornell Film, 1968; F-830 (Box 21-36-2566 - 19)
    "Game Show" educating consumers about the different forms of life insurance policies hosted, written and produced by Dr. Heinz B. Biesdorf. Produced by the College of Human Ecology.
  - "It's Your Money #3: Variations and Options" - Cornell Film - copy of F-830, 1968; DVD-1004 (Box 21-36-2566 - 19)
  - "Joyful Noises" - Cornell Film- Motion Picture Center, 1975; F-831 (Box 21-36-2566 - 19)
  - "Land in Jeopardy" - Cornell Film, 1968; F-832 (Box 21-36-2566 - 19)
  - "Land: With Love and Respect" - Cornell Film (also on video), 1979; F-833 (Box 21-36-2566 - 19)
  - "Cornell in Review" - Cornell Film, 1966-1967; F-834 (Box 21-36-2566 - 19)
  - "Loading and Unloading Heavy Equipment with on a Trailer" - Cornell Film, 1979; F-835 (Box 21-36-2566 - 19)
  - "Learning While They Play" - Cornell Film. (Use DVD-1002 in same box), 1965; F-839 (Box 21-36-2566 - 20)
    Discusses the importance of play on children's educational development. Project participants include Clara Baldwin and Dr. Helen T.M. Bayer. Produced by the College of Home Economics, Human Ecology.
  - "Learning While They Play" - copy of F-839, 1965; DVD-1002 (Box 21-36-2566 - 20)
  - "Measuring Up: Some Methods Employed in Nutrition Research" - Cornell Film. (Use DVD-999 in same box), 1966; F-840 (Box 21-36-2566 - 20)
    Discusses the research being done in the nutritional sciences including a study on how to measure the amount of body weight attributable to fat, the effects of vitamin B6 on the body for use in establishing national nutritional standards and the role calcium plays in the development of osteoporosis. Project participants include Professor Charlotte Young and Dr. Leo Luprock. Produced by the College of Home Economics, now Human Ecology.
  - "Measuring Up" - Copy of F-840, 1966; DVD-999 (Box 21-36-2566 - 20)
  - "Nutrition Sense and Nonsense" - Cornell Film. (Use DVD-997 in same box), 1962; F-842 (Box 21-36-2566 - 20)
    A consumer economics film advising people to be aware of modern "magic" remedies and diet fads that advertise quick and dramatic results.
  - "Nutrition Sense and Nonsense" - Copy of F-842, 1962; DVD-997 (Box 21-36-2566 - 20)